Charles Henry Armentrout V

www.linkedin.com/in/charmentroutv www.github.com/LegNBass charmentroutv@gmail.com

Present Address 5973 Dixon Dr. Raleigh, NC 27609 (336) 681-7224

Permanent Address 114 East Keeling Rd Greensboro, NC 27410

Career Profile

Passionate, lead software engineer who undertakes complex projects utilizing knowledge of Python, Docker, Bash, JavaScript, etc. Possesses practical experience in server-less architectures. Has experience with database administration and schema design, as well as application containerization and horizontal scaling applications. Also possesses strong interpersonal skills for successful team work and collaboration.

Professional Experience

Software Team Lead, The McClatchy Company, Raleigh NC

Feb 2020-Jan 2021

- · Manage and lead a team of remote engineers
- Architect and implement solutions for enterprise ETL processing
- Python, AWS (Lambda, Glue, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, etc), SQL

Senior Automation Architect, Credit Suisse, Durham, NC

Nov 2019-Feb 2020

- · Design and implement automation solutions for security response workflows.
- Python

Senior Software Engineer, Cisco Systems, Durham, NC

Jan 2017-Nov 2019

- Architect database schema for web application backend
- · Architect and implement REST API for web-to-backend communication in Flask
- Design and implement Network Devices testing platform in python
- Automate deployment of multiple applications with Docker and Docker-Compose
- Debug and Maintain Kubernetes-based application infrastructure
- · Python (Flask, SQLAlchemy, etc), Docker, SQL, Robot, TextFSM, Linux

Software Engineer, Deloitte, Morrisville, NC

Jul 2014-Jan 2017

- · Lead maintenance of legacy system.
- Implement infrastructure and orchestration of API based parallel service container platform using Docker, Apache Zookeeper, NGINX, Vagrant, and Cassandra DB.
- Develop and maintain full-stack web-facing applications utilizing a python backend.
- · Python (Flask, NumPy, Pandas, etc), Docker, Linux

Software Developer, ICF International, Martinsville, VA

Dec 2013-Jul 2014

- · Integrate applications with MS SQL Server, SharePoint, and other services
- Create custom web forms using JavaScript, HTML5, and ASP .NET with C#
- Design database schema to support projects and applications
- Automate previously manual reporting processes
- C# (ASP .NET), SQL, PowerShell

Analyst, Supplemental Software Solutions, Greensboro, NC

Sep 2012-Dec 2013

Education

Appalachian State University, Boone, NC

May 2012

- B.S. Finance and Banking
- B.S. Risk Management and Insurance

Computer Skills

<u>Languages:</u> Python, Go, Bash, JavaScript, HTML5, Haskell, C#, VBA Script, Batch, Perl, SQL,

CQL, LATEX

Frameworks/Systems: Flask, Docker, Docker-Compose, K8s, AWS (S3, Lambda, EC2, Glue,

Cloudformation, Cloudwatch), Git, Ansible, Jenkins, NGINX